

Ronan O'Leary

**Experienced Web Developer, Engineering/Web Team Lead** and Chief Technology Officer

(+31) 6 180 66136
roleary81@gmail.com
https://ronan-oleary.com, https://busylittlepixels.com
Github: github.com/RoOLeary LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ronanoleary

#### ABOUT ME

Hello, I'm Ronan. I'm a versatile, passionate and experienced Web Developer/Producer, Engineering Manager and Chief Technology Officer, with over 13 years professional experience. Coming from a web development background, my initial area of expertise was in front-end development, however, over time this broadened to wider areas of operation – I'm not shy of working with back-end languages, technologies and configurations. Additionally, I have extensive experience architecting and building custom web and software solutions, as well as possessing years of real-world, real-world experience growing, leading and managing dev teams.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Technical**

Web Development. JavaScript, PHP, Specialising in architecting, developing (and scaling) CMS applications and API-driven multi-sites with a range of tools including Next.jS, Payload CMS, Craft CMS, WordPress, GraphQL, Laravel, SCSS and Tailwind CSS, React.js, GIT, Gitlab, Cloudflare and third party integrations.

# Team Building/Leadership

Experienced team member, builder, leader. In my current position, I lead a young and dynamic team, developing innovative websites and applications using forward facing technologies and methodologies, for The Netherlands' fastest growing startup.

In my previous role, I reported directly to the CEO and liaised with the CTO and technical/p&e staff of the parent company(FT), and had 9 direct reports. I have significant experience recruiting and mentoring developers and shaping teams for growth, as well as setting long term business objectives and roadmaps.

In addition to mentoring and career development, I also regularly perform code and team reviews, hard and soft skill building, direct stakeholder engagement and experience speaking truth and finding creative and innovative solutions at the C-level.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Contracting - Fractional CTO/Tech Lead/Senior Developer

MARCH 2024 - Present

- Performing Fractional CTO services on contract in Amsterdam, Utrecht and (remotely) Dublin for events, martech and companies. Applying specialisms in the development of high volume recruitment sites, ATS integration and ecommerce solutions and strategies
- Team structuring, technical and architectural planning
- Infrastructure development (specialising in NextJS/TypeScript applications)
- Coaching team members in the development of bespoke web applications using modern frontend, Jamstack frameworks and libraries (NextJS/React)

# Picnic Technologies BV- Tech Lead, Web Team

NOVEMBER 2022 - MARCH 2024

- Leading the web team and execution of longer term company roadmaps for online operations
- Team and system architecture and project planning
- Team leadership, incident management and reporting
- Coaching team members in the development of bespoke web applications using modern frontend, Jamstack frameworks and libraries (NextJS/React)

Sites: https://jobs.picnic.app

# The Next Web BV. Amsterdam — Chief Technology Officer, Engineering Manager, Senior Web Developer/Producer, Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2017 - OCTOBER 2022

- Formerly CTO, direct report to CEO / board of management overseeing all product and engineering operations, teams, and strategies across five company pillars/verticals.
- Developed/oversaw a company's suite of 13+ websites and client sites.
- Directed and developed a large scale, 2 year platform migration/modernisation to a bespoke, headless multisite CMS solution for all properties. Integration of multiple platforms and systems.
- Managed and maintained all of the company web properties and lead optimisation pre and post migration to ensure consistent metrics.
- Developed bespoke solutions to facilitate move to online events during COVID19 and readaption of web product business strategy.
- Manage engineering team frontend, backend and data (x9 people)
- Developed bespoke features and manage the technical side of the editorial output including product roadmaps

Sites: thenextweb.com (all editorial, branded and sub-brand instances) thenextweb.com/conference, thenextweb.com/programs, thenextweb.com/spaces, thenextweb.com/dublin, hackthenormal.com

## Trigger Media, Dublin - Head of Web Development

OCTOBER 2016 - OCTOBER 2017

- Founded, developed and led the web team, developed custom and open source WaaS solutions to our client base, primarily WordPress/WooCommerce
- Direct design and development of websites
- Development of SEO and digital marketing solutions.
- Delivering pitches, tenders and active client acquisition through personal engagement.
- Implemented Client Service supports and set up development workflows

Sites: celticdublin.com, unitopsmedia.com

## Web Summit, Dublin - Senior Web Developer, Web Dev Team Lead

FEBRUARY 2014 - JULY 2016

- Joined (and eventually) led the web development team at leading global tech event company; Web Summit.
- Migrated several company sites to a single-platform (ExpressionEngine to WordPress migration) multisite instance.
- Developed various features and developer focussed activations.
- Built the fundamental web architecture ("Flexo") on top of WordPress, which provided (and still provides) the underlying framework for the company sites and applications, including jamstack instances.
- Direct report to VP of Engineering
- Lead and developed initial strategy to adopt headless/jamstack implementation of web product
- Managed web dev team (x 4 people)

Sites: websummit.com, collisionconf.com, riseconf.com

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Dublin Business School** — Higher Diploma

OCTOBER 2008 - OCTOBER 2010, DUBLIN, IRELAND

Higher diploma in Web Design and Development

#### Irish Academy of Public Relations - Higher Diploma

JULY 2002 - JULY 2004, DUBLIN, IRELAND

Higher diploma, Public Relations

# **University College Dublin, Dublin** — BA Politics/Irish language

SEPT 1999 - JUNE 2002, Dublin BA, Politics and Irish language

#### RFFFRFNCFS

Patrick De Laive, Co-founder; The Next Web Amsterdam, Netherlands, Ph: +31 6 42004200

# Paddy Ryan,

Co-founder & CTMO, Trigger Media Ltd.

Dublin, Ireland Ph: +353 85 155 3990

paddyatriggermediaco.com

# Jelle Van Wijhe

Formerly Head of Product, acting CTO - The Next Web BV

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Ph: +31 6 3754 5939